准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
欢迎来到
海之霸
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
快点  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
下班了
it's quitting time
我今晚有场牌要打
I've got a card game tonight
你要跟谁打牌  蟹老板
Who are you playing cards with, Mr. Krabs?
海之霸
我要去海之霸跟痞老板打
l'm going over to the Chum Bucket to play with Plankton
痞老板
Plankton
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
他可是你的死对头
he's your archenemy
偷蟹黄堡秘方偷了有好多年了
He's been trying to steal
the Krabby Patty formula for years
你干嘛跟他打牌
Why would you play cards with him?
我告诉你  你别传出去
Between you and me
全裤头村里就属痞老板牌打得最烂
Plankton is the worst card player in Bikini Bottom
十五年来  我每周四晚上
Why, I've been taking him to the cleaners
都能把他钱都给赢走
every Thursday night for 15 years
我不可能输
I never lose
把他钱都赢走
Taking him to the cleaners
真好笑
that's a hot one
昨天牌打得怎么样  蟹老板
How'd the card game go last night, Mr. Krabs?
我输了
I lost
见鬼了  蟹老板
Barnacles, Mr. Krabs
你输了多少钱
How much money did you lose?
我没输钱
I didn't lose any money
我输了
I lost
千万别说你输了蟹堡王
Don't tell me you lost the Krusty Krab
我输了
I lost
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
快说你没输掉
please tell me you didn't lose the
蟹黄堡的秘密配方
Krabby Patty secret formula
我
I
输了
lost
你
you
什么
What?
我拿你当赌注  然后我输了
I bet your contract and I lost
真好笑  蟹老板
Good one, Mr. Krabs
好了  我得去做蟹黄堡了
Well, I got to make those Krabby Patties
恐怕你再也不能在这工作了
I'm afraid you don't work here anymore
快说你没在开玩笑
Please tell me this isn't a joke
说啊  蟹老板
Go on, Mr. Krabs
跟他说
Tell him
说你开的玩笑有多残忍恶心
Tell him all about your cruel, sick joke
尽管我特爱残忍恶心的玩笑
As much as I love cruel, sick jokes
但我恐怕他没开玩笑
I'm afraid he's not joking
你现在要给我工作了  海绵宝宝
You work for me now, SpongeBob
该戴上海之霸桶型工作头盔了
Time to put on the official Chum Bucket bucket helmet
可是蟹老板
But, Mr. Krabs
我不想给他工作
I don't want to work for him
我要在这蟹堡王给你工作
I want to work for you here at the Krusty Krab
对不起  小子
I'm sorry, boy
都是我的错
It's all my fault
到底会是怎样冷酷无情的人
What kind of cold, heartless person
会拆散这样充满爱的感情
would break apart such a loving relationship?
就是我
I would
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
这可是你最大的失误  老螃蟹
This is your greatest blunder, Krabs
十五年来  我玩牌就是为了
For 15 years, I've been throwing those card games
等着你失手
just waiting for you to slip up
虽然蟹黄堡秘方并没有到我手上
I may not have the precious Krabby Patty formula
但是我拥有第二好的东西
but I've got the next best thing
就是做蟹黄堡的人
the guy who makes them
我马上就能让你倒闭了  老螃蟹
I'm going to run you out of business, Krabs
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
海之霸
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我能把胳膊要回来吗
Can I have my arms back?
这是哪里
What is this place?
科学
好了  我准备好拿蟹黄堡了
Okay, I'm ready for my Krabby Patty
其实
Actually, uh
痞老板  先生
Mr. Plankton, sir
我还没
I haven't, uh
可能你还不太明白
Perhaps you don't understand
你现在在给我工作
You work for me now
作为你的新老板
and as your new boss
我命令你马上给我做蟹黄堡
I command you to make me a patty this instant
否则我就只能摘掉你的脑子
or I'll be forced to remove your brain
装到我的机器厨师里面去
and implant it in my robot chef
那就开始做吧
So, get cooking
厨房
牌子上面写着厨房
The sign says "kitchen"
厨房
我的心上却写着监狱
but my heart says "jail"
无论身在何处  炉台仍是炉台
A stove is a stove no matter where you go
肉饼仍是肉饼  正是这样
A patty is a patty, that's what I say
烤架仍是烤架
A grill is a grill
确实是如此
This is surely so
无论如何  薯条仍是薯条
And fries should be fries either way
但这烤架不属于家
But this grill is not a home
炉台我也不熟悉
This is not the stove I know
我可以把它换过去  只愿你能够回来
I would trade it all away if you'd come back to stay
这间厨房没有你  不一样
This kitchen's not the same without you
只是一家小破店
It's just a greasy spoon
一家小破店
Just a greasy spoon
没有你
Without you
他在搞什么
What is he doing?
掉眼泪
All these tears?
还有乱唱歌
And the show tunes?
他怎么没在做蟹黄堡
Why isn't he making the patties?
算了
Forget it
启用B计划
I'm going with Plan B
把他脑子放到机器厨师里面去
I'll put his brain in the robot chef
你应该要清楚那样子没用的
You know that never works
答案很明显
The answer is obvious
要让海绵宝宝工作
To get to the SpongeBob
你必须要在他面前表现出同情与理解
you must show him compassion and understanding
这样他就会给你想要的东西了
Then he'll give you what you want
能不能别吵了
Will you be quiet?
我还在想办法
I'm thinking
想到了
I've got it
要让海绵宝宝工作
To get to the SpongeBob
我就得在他面前表现出同情与理解
I'll show him compassion and understanding
这样他就会给我想要的东西了
Then he'll give me what I want
嗨
Hi
对不起  痞老板
I'm sorry, Plankton
我尽力了
I'm trying my best
我不习惯这样子做蟹黄堡
I'm not used to cooking this way
求你别把我脑子弄出来
Please don't take my brain out
等等  海绵宝宝
Hold it, SpongeBob
我能同情和理解你
I'm capable of compassion and understanding
真的吗
Really?
那我想要回蟹堡王去
Then I'd like to go back to the Krusty Krab
别给我得寸进尺
Let's not get carried away
那我要怎样才能让你
Now, what can I do to make you
在海之霸工作得更舒服一点
more comfortable here at the Chum Bucket?
我一般用烤架做蟹黄堡
Well, I usually cook on a grill
没问题
You got it
虽说不容易  但总算弄来了
Well, it wasn't easy, but here it is
一个旧烤架
one old frying grill
要不要试用下
How about we try it out?
我只是
It's just that
习惯烤架朝那个方向
I'm used to the grill facing that way
不必多说
Say no more
我都会办妥的
I'll take care of everything
放这怎么样
How about here?
往左边一点点
A little more to the left
这样呢  海绵宝宝
How's this, SpongeBob?
再移一点点
Move it over a little more
这边呢
Here?
继续移
Keep going
这边呢
Here?
差不多了
Almost
可以了
That's it
再移一下
Just a little more
完美
Perfect
就放这了
Right there
不太对
I don't know
感觉哪里还是怪怪的
Something still doesn't feel right
再走几步  海绵宝宝
Just a few more steps, SpongeBob
好了  可以摘眼罩了
Okay, go ahead, take it off
这边把蟹堡王厨房丝毫不差仿过来了
lt's an exact replica of the Krusty Krab kitchen
还真是丝毫不差
It is an exact replica
水池在这
Here's the sink
油锅
The greasy fryers
吱吱叫的地板
The squeaky floorboards
还有那个玩意
And that thing
一份蟹黄堡马上来  蟹老板
One Krabby Patty coming up, Mr. Krabs
蟹老板
Mr. Krabs
别哭了  海绵宝宝
Don't cry, SpongeBob
我要让你知道  给我工作比较好
I'll show you it's much better working for me
还有什么是那小气老螃蟹不让给你的
ls there anything
that old skinflint Krabs wouldn't let you have?
有样东西我倒是一直很想要
Well, there is one thing l've always wanted
那你现在是不是心满意足
So, now do you have everything you need
要开始做蟹黄堡了吗
to make some Krabby Patties?
那个
Well
要开始做蟹黄堡了吗
Are you ready to make some patties?
等我吃完冰淇淋再说
Wait till I finish my ice cream
那蟹黄堡呢
How about those patties?
再快点  再快点
Faster, faster
然后最小的海精灵说
"And then the littlest sea elf said"
冷静  痞老板
Steady, Plankton
马上就要有回报了
lt's all going to pay off soon enough
你好啊  贪睡虫
Hey there, sleepyhead
怎么样了
What do you say?
准备来准备去的都让我饿死了
All that preparation is making me hungry
我也好饿
Me, too
你觉得现在要吃什么最好
You know what would really hit the spot?
要不你给咱做点蟹黄堡来吃
Why don't you whip us up a couple of Krabby Patties?
我现在比较想吃玉米卷
I'm kind of in the mood for tacos
不错嘛  海绵宝宝
Good one, SpongeBob
可是讲真  要不你去给咱做蟹黄堡吧
But really, why don't you go ahead and make us a patty
不要  我不太想吃蟹黄堡
Nah, I don't really feel like it
我真就不懂了
But I don't understand
烤架你有了  锅铲你有了
You have the grill and the spatula
舒服椅子你有了
and the comfy chair
你的臭脚我按摩了
I rubbed your putrid feet
我跟你讲  小东西
Tell you what, half-pint
等会再叫我做蟹黄堡
why don't you ask me later?
我命令你马上给我做蟹黄堡
I command you to make me a patty this instant
不做
No
别给我顶嘴
Don't back- sass me
说什么
What?
够了  先生
That's it, mister
你已经无权拥有脑子了
You just lost your brain privileges
做好了
Finished
海绵宝宝  快进来
SpongeBob, come in here
是不是应该要改叫机器海绵厨师宝宝
Or should I say RobotBob SpongeChefPants?
我都把脑子放到机器里面去了
l put the brain in the robot, you know
你就不该这么娇生惯养
You shouldn't have been a spoiled brat
看吧  我要什么就能有什么
You see, I always get what I want
我现在就要你给我做蟹黄堡
and I want you to make me a Krabby Patty
回答  等会再叫我
Response: Why don't you ask me later?
什么
What?
去做焊接了
Get welded
别走
Wait
我命令你给我做蟹黄堡
I command you, make me a Krabby Patty
油
我不要
I don't want to
蟹堡王
停业
老宝贝  我们要就此完结了
Well, old girl, this looks like our final chapter
我再也忍不了了
I can't take anymore
你得把那个黄色噩梦带回去
You've got to take that yellow nightmare back
根本就不值得
It's not worth it
我还是回去光明正大偷你蟹黄堡才好
I'm better off stealing a Krabby Patty fair and square
停业
已经都说好了  痞老板
Well, a deal's a deal, Plankton
他现在是你的麻烦了
He's your headache now
求你大发慈悲吧  蟹老板
Please have mercy, Krabs
我什么都可以做
I'll do anything
我求你了
I beg of you
要不你给我五十块
How about you give me 50 bucks
我把他从你那买回来
and I'll take him off your hands?
成交
It's a deal
反正我也抽老千了
I cheated anyway
现在快走吧  小虫子
Now, begone with you, you puny pest
我谢谢你了
Thank you
我跟我脑子很高兴能回来  蟹老板
My brain and I are glad to be back, Mr. Krabs
真高兴你回来了  小子
Good to have you back, lad
快去做蟹黄堡
Now, get to those patties
午餐高峰要到了
The lunch rush is a-coming
我不太想做
I don't feel like it
等会再说吧  蟹哥
Why don't you ask me later, Krabby?
我意思是  我今天白干活
I mean, I'm working all day for free
不要工钱
my treat
蟹堡王
就知道你会这么说
That's what I thought you said
铅笔人
导演
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
快看啊  这是在干什么
Well, well, what is this?
啊  是海上的画家
Ah, the artist at sea
我们来看看他辛勤创作的成果吧
Let us watch and see the fruits of his struggle
似乎他的灵感迸发出来了
It seems as if inspiration has struck
铅笔  怎么会
The pencil, what?
画家学到了在海上的第一堂课
The artist has learned the first lesson of the sea
备用铅笔一定要带好
Always bring a spare pencil
不要
No
行了
Okay
好了吗  派大星
ready, Patrick?
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
剪刀赢布  派大星
Scissors beats paper, Patrick
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
派大星  你怎么老是出布
Patrick, how come you always do paper?
那是个什么东西  海绵宝宝
What is that thing, SpongeBob?
好像是根大铅笔
lt looks like a giant pencil
去摸一下
Go touch it
还真是根大铅笔  派大星
It is a giant pencil, Patrick
来用这铅笔画大画吧
Let's draw some giant pictures with it
你在画什么
What you drawing?
退后  派大星
Stand back, Patrick
你往我脖子哈气  我画都画不了
I can't draw with you breathing down my neck
好个画家
Artists
画的是水母
It's a jellyfish
还挺好看  海绵宝宝
Pretty good, SpongeBob
不过这画缺乏基础结构
but it's lacking basic construction
你的透视仍有较多不足之处
and your perspective leaves a lot to be desired
人人都会乱评价
Everybody's a critic
海绵宝宝  你的画有生命力
SpongeBob, your drawing's coming to life
这还差不多  批评家
That's more like it, Mr. Critic
不对  我意思是它游走了
No, I mean it's swimming away
知道这样子什么意思吗  派大星
Do you know what this means, Patrick?
你的画没法挂进博物馆了
Your art can never hang in a museum
意思就是我们找到了根神奇铅笔
It means we found a magic pencil
现在就只要个神奇小胡子
Now all I need is a magic moustache
我所有梦想就会全都实现了
and all my dreams will have come true
马上就来
Coming right up
生活真美好
Life is good
来得快去得也快
Easy come, easy go
章鱼哥  要是你长了头发
Squidward, if you had some hair
就会是全海洋最帅的生物了
you'd be the most gorgeous creature in the sea
你长相好  才艺棒
You've got looks, talent
万事俱备  只欠满头
all you need is a full head of
秀发
hair
轮我了
My turn
小心点  派大星
Be careful, Patrick
当画家责任重大
Being an artist is a heavy responsibility
作的每幅画好比孩童  必须悉心呵护
Each work of art is like a child
and must be treated as such
没事  我只是要画漫画而已
Come on, I was just going to draw a cartoon
那你咋不早说
Okay, why didn't you say so?
又画了只水母
Another jellyfish
画的是章鱼哥  笨蛋
It's Squidward, silly
它动起来看着有点吓人
It's kind of creepy-looking when it moves
说得对  海绵宝宝
You're right, SpongeBob
不能放它进城
We can't let him go into town
章鱼哥好可怜
Poor Squidward
我刚想出了个好点子
My brain just hatched an idea
这绝对会超经典的
This is going to be classic
我要去公园散散步
I think I fancy a stroll around the park
章鱼哥
Squidward
你们要搞什么
What do you want
这什么东西
Hello, what's this?
有人送钱让我烫发
Someone left me some money for a perm
快让我多发帅哥拿
Come to Hairy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
我的头发
Oh, my hair
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
等下
Wait
我又有点子了
I've got another idea
这回的恶作剧是终极版
This'll be the ultimate prank
我画我自己  然后章鱼哥一开门
l'll draw me, and when Squidward answers the door
门外的就不是我了
it won't be me
看看人家啊
Look at him
好俊俏
Ain't he a doll?
就是差了个领带
All he needs is a tie
准备行动
Ready for action
他走到门口了
He's going to the door
他在敲门
He's knocking at the door
章鱼哥应门  然后就
Squidward's answering the door, and
他在打章鱼哥
He's beating up Squidward
铅笔人  住手
Doodle Boy, stop
他抢到铅笔了
He's got the pencil
我都干什么了
What have I done?
必须要找到他
We've got to find him
他可能会在哪里
Where could he possibly be?
可能是在那间潦草的菠萝屋里面
Maybe he's in that poorly drawn pineapple
开始行动
Come on, let's go
我不要进去
I'm not going in there
没事  派大星
Come on, Patrick
我就待在你身后
I'm right behind you
小步走
Baby steps
快到了
Almost there
刚刚那是怎么了
What just happened?
派大星  把我抬上去
Come on, Patrick, give me a boost up
咱就不能待在这安全的地方里面吗
Can't we just stay down here where it's safe?
不行
No way
这怪物出自我之手
I created this monster
所以我必须要阻止他
and I've got to stop him
懂我意思了吧  派大星
See what I mean, Patrick?
哪儿泄露了  大姐
Where's the leak, ma'am?
没事吧  派大星
You okay, Patrick?
芬兰
Finland
他就在那
There he is
他丑死了
He's hideous
看到他我就想吐
He makes me sick just looking at him
大凸眼
Those big, bulgy eyes
方身体  俩龅牙
that square body, those two buck teeth
笨领带
and that stupid tie
不过在你身上就很好看  海绵宝宝
But it looks good on you, SpongeBob
他把铅笔放下去了
He's putting down the pencil
时机到了
This is our chance
我数到三
On the count of three
惊 喜
就一起跳出去袭击他
we'll jump out and surprise him
居然有个惊喜派对
Oh, boy, a surprise party
今天他生日吗
Is it his birthday?
派大星  派大星
Patrick, Patrick
行动啊
Do something
生日快乐
Happy birthday
礼物送你
Here's your present
不客气
You're welcome
在那站好  铅笔人
Hold it right there, Doodle
我把你带到了这个世上
I brought you into this world
现在我要把你赶出这个世界
and now I'm going to take you out
有遗言吗
Any last words?
抱歉  说的什么
I'm sorry, what was that?
不要动  铅笔人
Hold still, Doodle
这都是为了你好
This is for your own good
尝尝那招  还有这招
Take that, and this
还有这招
and this
还有那招  还有这招
and that, and this
那招这招那招这招那招
that, this, that, this, that
我就是海绵宝宝  铲除邪恶之人
l am SpongeBob, destroyer of evil
放轻松
Take it easy
一幅画而已
it's just a drawing
反正完事了  对吧派大星
Well, that takes care of that, eh, Patrick?
确实完事了
Done and done
小蜗  你真早该得过去看看的
Gee, Gary, you should have been there
真的特刺激
It sure was exciting
不过其实  我有点想念铅笔人了
But, you know, I kind of miss the little doodle
他就像是我的孩子
He was like a son to me
反正我很高兴一切都正常了
But I am glad that things are back to normal
晚安了  小王子
Well, good night, sweet prince
小蜗
晚安了  神奇铅笔
Good night, magic pencil
神奇铅笔
Hey, magic pencil
你在干什么
What are you doing up?
给自己画杯水喝吗
Drawing yourself a glass of water?
铅笔人
DoodleBob
你应该没有生气吧
No hard feelings, right?
你到底想干什么  铅笔人
What do you think you're doing, Doodle?
你铅笔人
You Doodle
我海绵宝宝
Me SpongeBob
小心点使那玩意
Be careful with that thing
谁知道会有什么后果
Who knows what will happen?
鼻子知道了
I knows
觉得很好笑吧  铅笔人
Very funny, Doodle
现在轮我了
Now it's my turn
铅笔人  看来这样
Well, Doodle, it looks like this
作 画
才叫扯平
is a draw
也 有 笔 尖
你说到重点了
You've made your point
反正没事  我高中公认美术最好
No matter, I was voted "most artistic" in high school
海绵宝宝  你要给我付出代价
SpongeBob, you're going to pay for that
似乎是公认最笨拙才对
Maybe it was "most clumsy"
纸张
Paper
给铅笔人先生来一页
Page for Mr. Doodle
海绵宝宝  这乱糟糟的是怎一回事
Hey, SpongeBob, what's with all the ruckus?
自己来看吧  派大星
Take a look for yourself, Patrick
是那个邪恶的涂鸦
It's the evil doodle
错了  不邪恶
No, no, not evil
他只是个二维生物
He was just a two-dimensional creature
在我们的三维海底世界迷了路
lost in our three-dimensional aquatic world
寻求自己命中的目标
longing for a purpose
所以说
So
他就一副画了
he's a drawing?
完全没错
Exactly
看人家多开心啊
See how happy he is?
还是看着有点吓人
He still looks kind of creepy
伟大的神奇铅笔啊
O great magic pencil
我们海洋生物无法驾驭你的力量
your powers are too mighty for us ocean dwellers
故我要把你送回你原先的神奇王国去
so I will send you back
to the magic kingdom from where you came
准备好了吗  派大星
Are you ready, Patrick?
好了
Ready
我们回过来看这深陷创作低谷的画家
We rejoin the artist in a creative slump
这
What's
什么东西
what's this?
是我的铅笔
My pencil
海上画家的第二条重要规则就是
The second most important rule for the artist at sea
转笔刀一定要带好
Always bring a pencil sharpener
不要
No